Okay, module four, essential life skills.
This is something that I had to learn by hand,
just on my own.
And there are some things that'll surprise you
about how to do these simple things.
The objectives, complete basic independent living tasks,
grocery shopping on a budget, laundry, simple cooking,
explain the basics of health insurance
as it applies to a college student.
Health insurance is actually really important
if you wanna go into campus health.
When I was a freshman, it was the COVID pandemic.
So I had to go into campus health
and go get tested and you needed insurance for that.
Identify the key things to understand
before signing a lease.
Now, I've lived in an apartment
the last two years of my undergraduate time
and knowing the lease is extremely important,
how much you owe per month,
how much the utilities might be per month.
Assess your own readiness across these life skills
and make a plan for the gaps.
So with these independent life skills,
I'm gonna be teaching you about simple cooking.
What are the basic things that you might need
to make a meal and make many meals out of that?
Laundry.
Laundry was hard for me.
As freshmen, everybody goes into the laundry room
at the same time and you might find yourself
waiting like two hours.
Make sure that if your college has a laundry room
and it has an app to reserve these laundry machines
that you utilize that.
And you might not even need like the full tubs of detergent
or the full tubs of bleach or whatever.
I really got through with just laundry pods,
tied laundry pods, some of them are really cheap.
Every grocery store may have their own name brand
of laundry pods, very important to know.
Grocery shopping, I had a target at Chapel Hill
that I would go to shopping maybe hard
depending on where you're at, where your college is.
If you're even near grocery store at all.
So you got to plan for that
and plan for the gaps that you may not know.
Signing a lease, looking at apartments.
If you're not on campus, you got to look at your apartments.
How much you expect to make.
That's where the budgeting comes in.
But yeah, these essential life skills,
I feel like shouldn't be too much.
But if you plan on doing laundry right after doing this,
this module, I hope it works well for you.
Make sure you utilize those name brand.
Like you don't have to do name brand.
Make sure you utilize the cheapest
and effective options that you have at your disposal.